

# **BRYAN WINDSOR**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | TAIDAID.COM | WINDSOR.BRYAN@GMAIL.COM

## WHY ME

As a software engineer with experience in management and education, I have a background that is relevant to all stakeholders, provides me unique insights, the ability to fully understand a project, and work well in a team. My experiences with the MERN stack have given me the tools to build exciting, responsive, and lightning-fast apps. Breaking down complex topics into digestible components is second nature to me and I have gone through the grind of extensive learning again and again. I have lived abroad for 5 years in 3 countries and traveled through more than 15. I speak fluent English and Chinese and can communicate in Dutch and French as well.

# **MATCHING COMPETENCIES**

#### COMMUNICATION

Years of experience in technical management and development, education, and foreign cultures have fostered a high level of clear verbal and written communication including technical writing.

#### PROBLEM SOLVING

Problem-solving is a passion of mine and something I do for fun in my free time. I love puzzles, optimization, and critical thinking and I hone these skills in coding, bouldering, language-learning, gaming, and teaching.

#### **ACCOUNTABILITY**

Following-up, taking notes, organizing, and planning are skills that I have developed over many years as a professional. I am known for taking the lead through uncertain territory, acquiring resources, and ensuring proper accounting of time, objectives, and resources.

### **BROAD EXPERIENCE**

Experiences as a client and a vendor, a leader and a follower, a freelancer and an employee, have instilled the drive and background to understand all aspects of a project as well as the ability to communicate these aspects to anyone involved.

# RELEVANT SKILLS

#### JavaScript **TypeScript** Node.js React.js Agile / Scrum D3.js Redux Git Jest / Enzyme Docker Linux / Mac Shell/Bash CSS / SCSS Firebase HTML5 Bootstrap MongoDB REST / JSON Project Mgmt. PostgreSQL English Mandarin Dutch French

# CONTACT

- linkedin.com/in/bryanwindsor
- +31616767007

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER II • CLOCKWORK • SEP 2019 - PRESENT

The Clockwork team working with Rabobank developed a method for identifying, presenting, and tracking innovation opportunities and needed to be able to digitize and automate their methodology.

- Create basic design framework
- Provide initial backend functionality
- Build front-end application
- Visualize data using D3.js's Zoomable Sunburst graph
- Delegate development tasks
- Create development backlog and sprints with product owner

**Tools & Methodologies:** Agile / Scrum; CSS; Git; HTML; JavaScript; Jira; JSON; Project Management; ES6; Express; Visual Studio Code; REST; Node.js; Firebase; React.js; Redux; D3.js

#### TEACHER • VIPKID • AUG 2017 - SEP 2019

East Asia has a giant industry for teaching English to Chinese speakers. My Mandarin abilities gave me a unique position to capitalize on this demand.

- 2400+ classes
- 460 students
- 1197/1207 excellent reviews
- Coach students in pronunciation with speech therapy methods
- Guide students to proper hand-writing techniques and resources
- Educate students in grammar
- Train students' listening ability

#### FULLSTACK DEVELOPER • FREELANCE • JAN 2019 - SEP 2019

As a freelance developer, I designed and built several different apps of interest for potential use.

# **The Weather App**

github.com/taidaid/weatherapp

A lightweight React app for displaying the weather information via a user's location, a location's name, or coordinates. The app was designed to showcase a minimalist design with intuitive functionality and responsive styling. In addition to integrating API data, the app made use of the Chart.js library for beautiful and informative graphs.

Tools & Methodologies: CSS; Git; HTML; JavaScript; JSON; REST; React.js; Darksky API; Chart.js

# **SoundUp**

github.com/taidaid/SoundUp

Two engineers building a startup app had obstacles in finishing their project, particularly with back-end/API integration and UI styling and functionality.

Tools & Methodologies: CSS; Git; JavaScript; JSON; Node.js; Express; MongoDB; REST; React.js; Spotify API

# Face-recognition App

github.com/taidaid/face-detection

This app was built as the final project for The Complete Web Developer 2019 course. It is a clean, smooth, and lightweight app that accepts any image URL and returns the same image with outlines around each face in the photo.

Tools & Methodologies: CSS; Git; HTML; JavaScript; JSON; PostgreSQL; Node.js; Express; REST; Clarifai API

#### TEACHER • HEAD START • AUG 2015 - SEP 2017

Taiwan has a large demand for native English-speaking teachers and an even higher demand for those that also speak Mandarin.

- Mentor students in English public speaking
- Coach pronunciation
- Guide projects and activities
- Determine lesson plans and learning objectives
- Administer exams

#### DIGITAL MARKETING DIRECTOR • NATIONAL PAIN CARE • JUN 2013 - JUN 2015

National Pain Care needed to increase its brand awareness and conversion rates.

- Develop a web presence with 1 national informational website, a regional informational site per practice (4), and a localized site per clinic (15).
- Manage radio and TV ads
- Assess budget and provide performance metrics
- Integrate Prime Suite with websites

#### IT OPERATIONS DIRECTOR • NATIONAL PAIN CARE • AUG 2011 - JUN 2014

National Pain Care was a healthcare management startup. After acquiring several smaller clinics, it needed to reduce redundant equipment and services while increasing its disaster recovery ability and security.

- Virtualize, centralize, and secure server environment
- Secure and standardize client environment
- Completed IT overhaul for 15 locations and 300 employees
- Implemented and supported EMR software
- Implement full-mesh WAN
- Create call centers
- Train in-house IT staff

#### INTERIM PRACTICE MANAGER • GEORGIA PAIN PHYSICIANS • JAN 2012 - JUN 2012

Georgia Pain Physicians, a subsidiary of National Pain Care, found itself without a practice manager for a period of 6 months.

- Oversee 4 locations' clinic operations
- Manage medical assistant and technician staff
- Handle patient disputes
- Manage partner and vendor relationships and projects
- Provide new hire training in EHR and clinic operations

# **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

#### COMPLETE REACT DEVELOPER IN 2019 (W/REDUX, HOOKS, GRAPHQL)

Andrei Neagoie - In progress

# THE COMPLETE JUNIOR TO SENIOR DEVELOPER ROADMAP

Andrei Neagoie - In progress

#### **UNDERSTANDING TYPESCRIPT - 2020 EDITION**

Maximilian Schwarzmuller - In progress

#### **BUILD DATA VISUALIZATIONS WITH D3.JS & FIREBASE**

Shaun Pelling – Nov 2019

#### **ADVANCED JAVASCRIPT CONCEPTS**

Andrei Neagoie – Oct 2019

#### **REACT, REDUX, & ENZYME - INTRODUCING APPS & TESTS**

David Joseph Katz – Aug 2019

#### THE COMPLETE WEB DEVELOPER IN 2019

Andrei Neagoie – Aug 2019

#### THE REACT COURSE

Flavio Copes – Jul 2019

### **CERTIFIED B2 MANDARIN CHINESE**

National Taiwan Normal University - Aug 2014 - Sep 2017

#### **BBA - MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEMS**

University of Georgia – Aug 2006 – May 2011

# **SPECIALIZATIONS & METHODOLOGIES**

CSS	***	D3.js	***
ES6	***	React.js	***
HTML	***	JavaScript	***
Education	***	Training	***
REST / JSON	***	Healthcare	***
Project Management	***	Typescript	**
Node.js	**	Express.js	**
Firebase	**	MongoDB	**
Agile / Scrum	**	Linux	**
SQL	**	SCSS	**
MacOS	**	Windows	**
Application/System Design	**	PostgreSQL	*
MS Access	*	Java	*
Python	*	XML	*

# **LANGUAGES**

	<u>Verbal</u>	<u>Written</u>
Dutch	Basic	Basic
English	Native	Native
Mandarin	Excellent	Good
French	Basic	Basic